Amir Elmishali, Ph.D

0524506071 \(\phi\) amir9979@gmail.com \(\phi\) amir9979.github.io \(\phi\) linkedin.com/in/amir-elmishali/

Al and data science researcher with 7+ years of experience researching, developing and advising on Al projects. Ph.D. in software and systems engineering with expertise in machine learning techniques for software engineering. I seek a position as a data scientist to grow my career further.

Education

Ph.D., Ben-Gurion University of the Negev, Israel

2016 - 2021

Department of Software and Information Systems Engineering

Dissertation topic: Artificial Intelligence Techniques for Automated Bug Prediction and Detection.

Supervised by Professor Meir Kalech and Professor Roni Stern.

M.Sc, Ben-Gurion University of the Negev, Israel

2014 - 2016

Department of Software and Information Systems Engineering

GPA: 93.06/100

Supervised by Professor Meir Kalech and Professor Roni Stern. Member of "Meitar" Excellence Program, started M.Sc during B.Sc.

B.Sc, Ben-Gurion University of the Negev, Israel

2011 - 2015

Department of Software Engineering. Outstanding Performance Award.

GPA: 89.05/100

Experience

Postdoctoral Researcher

2021

Anomaly Detection and Diagnosis lab, Ben-Gurion University of the Negev

I researched and supervised students in AI and machine learning projects for software engineering.

Ph.D Summer Internship

2020

Facebook

Research and implementation of a feature recommendation system for data scientists at Facebook.

Teaching Assistant

2017-2021

Ben-Gurion University

Crafted and lectured on content in courses for undergraduate software engineering students: "Introduction to Software Engineering" (2020) and "Workshop on Software Engineering Project" (2021). Supervising projects in the courses "Fault Diagnosis in Artificial Intelligence" (2017-2021) and "Research Skills" (2018-2021).

Research Assistance 2013 - 2014

Anomaly Detection and Diagnosis lab, Ben-Gurion University of the Negev

Research and implementation of software defect prediction models based on repository mining.

Military Service

R&D Software Engineer

2015 - 2019

8200 Intelligence Unit. IDF

Development of C++ and Python platform for cyber-security applications for Windows.

Skills

Data Science: Data exploration, Research, Data pre-processing, Feature engineering, Classification, Clustering, Deep learning, Evaluation metrics, Visualization, Statistics.

Coding: Python (Scikit-Learn, Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, PyTorch, TensorFlow), Java, C++, SQL, Environments (Pycharm, Jupyter Notebook, IPython), OOP, Design patterns, Git, CI/CD.

Personal: Teamwork, Time management, Project Lead, Agile, Presentation.

Awards and Honors

IDF's outstanding scientist

2018

Recommended by commander of the Israeli intelligence corps, IDF

B.Sc outstanding performance award

2015

Journal Articles

1. **Elmishali, Amir**, Stern Roni, and Kalech Meir. "Diagnosing Software System Exploits." IEEE Intelligent Systems (2020).

Impact factor of IEEE Intelligent Systems 2020 is: 3.405, 53/140, Q2

2. **Elmishali, Amir**, Stern Roni, and Kalech Meir. "An Artificial Intelligence paradigm for troubleshooting software bugs." Engineering Applications of Artificial Intelligence 69 (2018).

Impact factor of Engineering Applications of Artificial Intelligence-18 is: 3.526, 15/88, Q1

Conference Proceedings

1. **Elmishali, Amir**, Sotto-Mayor Bruno, Roshanski Inbal, Sultan Amit and Kalech Meir. "BEIRUT: Repository Mining for Defect Prediction." IEEE 32st International Symposium on Software Reliability Engineering (ISSRE) 2021.

Rank: A

2. Hershkovich Eran, Abreu Rui, Stern Roni and **Elmishali, Amir**. "Prioritized Test Generation Guided by Software Fault Prediction". IEEE International Conference on Software Testing, Verification and Validation (ICST) 2021.

Rank: A

- Elmishali, Amir, Stern Roni, and Kalech Meir. "DeBGUer: A Tool for Bug Prediction and Diagnosis." Proceedings of the AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence. Vol. 33. 2019.
 - Rank: A*
- 4. **Elmishali, Amir**, Stern Roni, and Kalech Meir. "Data-augmented Software Diagnosis." Twenty-Eighth IAAI Conference. 2016.

Rank: A*

Patents

1. Kalech, Meir, Ron Stern, and **Elmishali, Amir**. "Data-augmented software diagnosis method and a diagnoser therefor." U.S. Patent No. 10,437,702. 8 Oct. 2019.

Workshop Articles

- 1. **Elmishali**, **Amir** and Kalech Meir. "Issue-Driven Features for Software Fault Prediction" . 32nd International Workshop on the Principles of Diagnosis (DX'21)
- 2. Mordoch Argaman, Natan Avraham **Elmishali, Amir**, and Kalech Meir. "Bugs Assignment for Workload Distribution". 32nd International Workshop on the Principles of Diagnosis (DX'21)
- 3. Sotto-Mayor Bruno, **Elmishali, Amir**, Kalech Meir and Abreu Rui. "Exploring Designite for Smell-Based Defect Prediction". 31st International Workshop on the Principles of Diagnosis (DX'20)
- 4. Hershkovich Eran, Abreu Rui, Stern Roni and **Elmishali, Amir**. "Prediction-Guided Software Test Generation". 30th International Workshop on the Principles of Diagnosis (DX'19).
- 5. Roshanski Inbal, Kalech Meir, Stern Roni and **Elmishali, Amir**. "The Cold Start Problem in Software Fault Prediction". 30th International Workshop on the Principles of Diagnosis (DX'19).
- 6. **Elmishali, Amir**, Stern Roni, and Kalech Meir. "DeBGUer: A Tool for Bug Prediction and Diagnosis." 29th International Workshop on the Principles of Diagnosis (DX'18).
- 7. **Elmishali, Amir**, Stern Roni, and Kalech Meir. "Diagnosing System Exploits." 28th International Workshop on the Principles of Diagnosis (DX'17).
- 8. **Elmishali, Amir**, Stern Roni, and Kalech Meir. "Data-augmented Software Diagnosis." 26th International Workshop on the Principles of Diagnosis (DX'15).